Finding Aid for the Rob Roy Purdy Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings by Others
  - Boas, George “The Humanities and the Sciences” Boswell, George W. “Five Choice Tennessee Folk Songs” (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Bond, Richmond P. “Eighteenth Century Correspondence: A Survey” (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Bowling, Lawrence Edward “Faulkner: The Theme of Pride in The Sound and the Fury”; “The Thematic Framework of Romeo and Juliet”
    “Thoreau’s Social Criticism as Poetry”; “William Faulkner: The Importance of Love”
  - Braddy, Haldeen “Chaucer and Graunson: The Valentine Tradition”; “Chaucer’s Book of the Duchess and Two of Granson’s (Box 17, Folder 7)
    Complaintes”;” Chaucer’s Comic Valentine”; “Chaucer’s Don Pedro and the Purpose of The Monk’s Tale”; “The Date of Chaucer’s Lak of Steadfastnesse”; “New Documentary Evidence Concerning Chaucer’s Mission to Lombardy”; “On Rereading Chaucer”; “Three Chaucer Notes”; “the Two Petros in the ‘Monkes Tale’”
  - Bradford, Melvin E. “Faulkner’s ‘Tall Men’”; “Faulkner and the Jeffersonian Dream: Nationalism in ‘Two Soldiers’ and ‘Shall not Perish’”; “Brotherhood in ‘The Bear’: An Exemplum for Critics”; “How Soon the Winter: Meaning and Metaphor in Donald Davidson’s ‘A Touch of Snow’” (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Branscomb, Harvie “The Contribution of Moral and Spiritual Ideas to the Making of the American Way of Life”; “Intercollegiate Athletics in the Southern Association”; $20,000,000 a Year Spent Right Here: What the Colleges Contribute to the economy of Nashville” (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Brie, Friedrich “The Deceyte of Women: aelteste englishche Novellensammlung (1547) (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Bryant, Joseph Allen “Brief Articles and Notes”; “Milton and the Art of History: A Study of Two Influences on a Brief History of Moscovia” “Milton’s Views on Universal and Civil Decay”; “The Nature of the Conflict in Jonson’s Sejanus”; “ A Note of Milton’s Use of Machiavelli’s Discorsi” (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Bryson, Frederick Robertson “The Point of Honor in Sixteenth Century Italy: As Aspect of the Life of the Gentleman” (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Busby, Olive Mary “Studies in the Development of the Fool in the Elizabethan Drama” (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Campbell, Harry Modean “The Hanging Scene in Melville’s Billy Budd, Foretopman”; “Structural Devices in the Works of Faulkner”; “Warren as Philosopher in World Enough and Time” (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Carpenter, Nan Cooke “Music in the Secunda Pastorum”; “ Rabelais and the Chanson” (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Cate, Wirt Armistead “The Problem of the Origin of the Griselda Story” (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Chambers, A.B. “Absalom and Achitophel: Christ and Satan”; “ The Meaning of the ‘Temple’ in Donne’s La Corona” Clarke, Robert T. “Herder, Percy, and the Song of Songs” (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Coffman, George R. “The Mediaeval Academy, Evaluation and Reevaluation”; “Old Age from Horace to Chaucer: Some Literary Affinities and Adventures of an Idea” (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Cohen, Joseph “In Memory of W.B. Yeats and Wilfred Owen”; “Isaac Rosenberg: From Romantic to Classic”; “ Wouk’s Morningstar and Hemingway’s Sun” (Box 17, Folder 19)
- Writings by Others
  - Crow, Martin M. “Materials for a New Edition of the Chaucer Life – Records” Cunningham, J. V. “Essence” and the Phoenix and Turtle (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Curry, Walter Clyde “Chauntecleer and Pertelote on Dreams”; “ The Consistence and Qualities of Milton’s Chaos”; “ The Genesis of Milton’s World”; “Milton’s Chaos and Old Night”; “ Some Travels of Milton’s Satan and the Road to Hell” (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Davidson, Donald “To the Warders of the Gate” (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Delzell, Charles F. “The European Federalist Movement in Italy: First Phase, 1918 -1947”; “Italy in Modern Times: An Introduction to the Historical Literature in English”; Review of “ Mussolini’s Italy Twenty Years After” (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Dempster, Germaine “A Chapter of the Manuscript History of the Canterbury Tales”; “ Did Chaucer Write An Holy Medytacion?”; “ A Period in the Development of the Canterbury Tales Marriage Group and of Blocks B2 and C” (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Duncan, Edgar Hill “The Alchemy in Jonson’s Mercury Vindicated”; “’Bear in Hand’ in The Wife of Bath’s Prologue”; “ Jonson’s Alchemist and the Literature of Alchemy”; “The Yeoman’s Canon’s ‘Silver Citrinacioun’”; The Humanities in Higher Education in the South (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Fairfield, Roy P. “A Decade of ‘Cultch’” (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Finney, Claude Lee “Keats’s Philosophy of Negative Capability in its Philosophical Backgrounds” (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Gates, W.B. “Cooper’s Indebtedness to Shakespeare”; “Cooper’s The Crater and Two Explorers (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Gayre of Gayre, R. “ The Mankind Quarterly Under Attack” (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Gerould, Gordon Hall “The Social Status of Chaucer’s Franklin” (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Graves, Thornton Shirley “The Court and the London Theatres During the Reign of Elizabeth” (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Gray, Henry David “The Original Version of ‘Love’s Labour’s Lost’ with a conjecture as to ‘Love’s Labour’s Won’” (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Graydon, Joseph “ Defense of Criseyde” Harder, Kelsie “Charactonyms in Faulkner’s Novels” (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Hardie, Robert H., et. Al. “On Reducing the Periodic Error in a Telescope Drive”; “Photoelectric Reductions”; “ Three – Color Photometry of 56 Arietis”; Three – Color Photometry of cy Aquarii”; Dyer Observatory Report, 1963 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Hildago, Carlos F. “Juan Ramon Molina, the Poet of Honduras” (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Hitt, Ralph E. “Chauntecleer as Mock-Hero of the ‘Nun’s Priest’s Tale’” Hodges, John C. “Fresh MS Sources for a Life of William Congreve” (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Hollins Critic “Hard Times and the Noble Savage: J.P. Donleavy’s A Singular Man” by John Rees Moore; “John Cheever and the Charms of Innocence: The Craft of The Wapshot Scandal” by George Garrett; “Hunting a Master Image: The Poetry of Richard Eberhart” by Daniel Hoffman; “The Search for Lost Innocence: Karl Shapiro’s The Bourgeois Poet” by Louis D. Rubin, Jr.; “The Long Chronicle of Guilt: William Golding’s The Spire” by Walter Sullivan (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Horrell, Joe “Chaucer’s Symbolic Plowman” Hudson, Robert Lofton “The Sermon as Teaching with Special Emphasis on Motivation” (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Hulbert, James R. “Beowulf and the Classical Epic” (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Hunt, Douglas L. “The Life and Work of Charles Hoyt” Hunter, William B., Jr. “ Milton on the Nature of Man”; “Poe’s ‘The Sleeper’ and Macbeth (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Huppe, Bernard F. “The Authorship of the A and B Texts of Piers Plowman (Box 18, Folder 22)
- Writings by Others
  - Kern, Alfred Allan “The Ancestry of Chaucer” (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Kirby, T.A. Review of The Gawain Poet: Studies in His Personality and Background Long, Hudson “Sut Lovingood and Mark Twain’s Joan of Arc (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Lumiansky, R. M. “The Function of the Proverbial Monitory Elements in Chaucer’s Troilus and Criseyde” (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - McGalliard, John C. “Chaucer’s ‘Merchant’s Tale’ and Deschamps’ Miroir de Mariage” (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Mims, Edwin “John Maurice Webb, 1847 - 1916”; “Woodrow Wilson: The Happy Warrior” (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Moore, Arthur K. “Chaucer’s Lost Songs”; “The Eyen Greye of Chaucer’s Prioress”; “The Pardoner’s Interruption of the Wife of Bath Prologue”; “ Types of the Folk Song ‘Father Grumble’”; “The Setting of the Tua Mariit Wemen and athe Wedo”; “Some Implications of the Middle English Craft of Lovers” (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Nixon, H.C. “ A Thirty Years’ Personal View”; “The Southern Governor’s Conference as A Pressure Group” (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Norton, Herman “Revivalism in the Confederate Armies” (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Owen, Charles A., Jr. “The Role of the Narrator in the ‘Parlement of Foules’” Ownbey, E. Sydnor “Merlin and Arthur: A Study of Merlin’s Character and Function in the Romances Dealing with the Early Life of Arthur” (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Owsley, Harriet Chappell “Henry Shelton Sanford and Federal Surveillance Abroad, 1861 - 1865” Parks, Edd Winfield “ Howells and the Gentle Reader” (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Parr, Johnstone “The Horoscope of Mycetes in Marlowe’s Tamburlaine I; “The Site and Ancient City of Browning’s Love Among the Ruins; “ Astronomical Dating for Some of Lydgate’s Poems”; Edmund’s Nativity in King Lear”; “The Duke of Byron’s Malignant Caput Algol”; “ Horoscope in Webster’s The Duchess of Malfi”; “Sources of the Astrological Prefaces in Robert Greene’s Planetomachia” (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Patch, Howard R. Patch “Precious Stones in The House of Fame”; “ Necessity in Boethius and the Neoplatonists”; “Chaucer and the Common People”; “Chaucer and Mediaeval Romance” Phillips, Dayton “Ferguson’s History of the Periodic Conception of the Renaissance” (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Powell, Arnold F. “The Melting Mood: A Study of the Function of Pathos in English Tragedy through Shakespeare” (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Pratt, Robert A. “Giovanni Sercambi, Speziale”; “’Joye After Wo’ in the Knight’s Tale”; “ Chaucer and the Hand that Fed Him”; “The Order of the Canterbury Tales”; “Was Robyn the Miller’s Youth Misspent?”; “Review: the Literary Relationships of Chaucer’s Tale (J.B. Severs)”; Chaucer’s Claudian” (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Pratt, Robert A. “Chaucer’s ‘Natal Jove’ and ‘Seint Jerome.. .Agayn Jovinian’”; “Jankyn’s Book of Wikked Wyves: Medieval Antimatrimonial Propaganda in the Universities”; “Saint Jerome in Jankyn’s Book of Wikked Wyves”; “ Symkyn Koude ‘Turne Coppes’: the Reeves Tale 3928”; “Chaucer and the Pillars of Hercules” (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Ransom, Ellene “Utopus Discovers America or Critical Realism in American Utopian Fiction, 1798 - 1900” - summary of a thesis (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Roberts, Henry L. “Recent Books on International Relations” (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Rosenblatt, Maurice “Drumhead Justice: the Facts about Army Courts Martial” (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Rysan, Josef “Mythological Solution of Crisis: a Parallet between Luther’s and Hitler’s Germany”; “Is Our Civilization Creating a New Folklore?” (Box 19, Folder 19)
- Writings by Others
  - Sanborn, Herbert C. “Desegregation and Ethics”; “The Democratic Control of Education”; “Lines for a ‘Dying Republic’”; “The Meeting Point of Philosophy and Psychology”; Methodology and the Monkey States”; “Methodology and the Problem of Musical Expression”; “Dingler’s Methodical Philosophy” (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Seeger, Raymond J. “Galileo, Yesterday and Today” (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Sellers, James “The Almost Chosen People: A Theological Approach to American Society” (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Sensabaugh, George “Burton’s Influence on Ford’s The Lover’s Melancholy” (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Silberman, Lou H. “Judaism in the United States in the Early Nineteenth Century”; “The Paradoxes of Freedom and Authority” (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Slaughter, Eugene Edward “ ‘Allas!Allas! That Ever Love Was Sinne!’”; “Every Vertu at His Reste’”; “Love and the Virtues and Vices in Chaucer” Smith, Roland M. “Three Obscure English Proverbs”; “The Six Gifts”; Review of The Works of Edmund Spenser (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Spears, Monroe K. Review of The Enchafed Flood; “ Christopher Fry and the Redemption of Joy”; “The Meaning of Matthew Prior’s Alma”; “ Matthew Prior’s Attitude Toward Natural Science”; “The Failure of Language” (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Spears, Monroe K. “The Criticism of Allen Tate” (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Spears, Monroe K. Review “The Mysterious Urn”; “The Southern Vanguard”; “Matthew Prior’s Religion” (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Steadman, J.M. “The Ingeld Episode in Beowulf: History or Prophecy?” (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Stevens, Wallace “Two or Three Ideas” Stevenson, John W. “The Literary Reputation of Stephen Crane” Stillwell, Gardiner “Unity and Comedy in Chaucer’s Parlement of Foules” (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Stewart, Randall “Editing The American Notebooks”; “The Relation Between Fugitives and Agrarians” Svendsen, Kester “The New Damoetas” (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Swan, Donald “Genetics and psychology”; A Rorschach study of the development of personality structure in white and negro children in a southeastern community” (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Tavenner, Eugene “Roman Moon Lore”; “The Amulet in Roman Curative Medicine” (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Thaler, Alwin “’The Devil’s Crest’ in Measure for Measure”; “ Literary Criticism in a Mirror for Magistrates” (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Touster, Eva “Metrical Variations as a Poetic Device in Beowulf” Walker, Curtis “Eleanor of Aquitaine and the Disaster at Cadmos Mountain on the Second Crusade” (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Watkins, Floyd “The Political Career of James Kirke Paulding”; “James Kirke Paulding and the South”; “James Kirke Paulding’s Early Ring-Tailed Roarer”; “ The Southern Mountaineers’ Archaic English”; Thomas Wolfe and the Nashville Agrarians”; “Thomas Wolfe and the Southern Mountaineer”; “Notes and Queries: ‘Benito Cereno’: A Note in Rebuttal”; “Flaubert, Yeats and the National Library” (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - West, Robert “Milton’s Angelological Heresies” Willems, Von Emilio “Protestantismus und Kulturwandel in Brasilien und Chile” (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Wright, Louis B. “The Reading of Renaissance English Women”; “Madmen as Vaudeville Performers on the Elizabethan Stage” Zeek, C.F. “Balzac as a Business Man” (Box 20, Folder 19)
- Collection of Publications
  - Carnegie Corporation of New York Quarterly, July 1957 - April 1959 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - CEA Critic - Newsletter of the College English Association (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Council for Basic Education Bulletin, 1957 - 1959 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Davidson College Bulletin, August 1958 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Howard College Bulletin “ Shakespeare and the Troy Story ”, June 1922 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Inside the ACD - Notes and Questions on American English, issues from, 1948 - 1955 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - ITEMS - Social Science Research Council, June 1950, September 1958 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - The Mole, November 1949, May 1950 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - The Shakespeare Newsletter, 1951, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - South Atlantic Bulletin, May 1957 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Tennessee Folklore Society Bulletin, December 1952 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - The Superior Student - Newsletter of the Inter-University Committee on the Superior Student, 1958 - 59 (Box 21, Folder 13)
- Collection of Publications
  - What the Colleges are Doing - No. 87, Spring 1950; No. 95, January 1953; No. 102, Spring 1955; No. 103, Fall 1955 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - What the Colleges are Doing - No. 106, Fall 1956; No. 107, Winter 1957; No. 109, December 1957; No. 111, May 1958; No. 113, Winter 1959 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Word Study (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Word Study (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - “Literature, Art, and Social Change in England, 1789 -1870” - University of London program booklets (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets and reprints - Business and Industry (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets and reprints - Business and Industry (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Educational (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Educational - Teachers and training (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Educational - other universities (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Educational - other universities (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Educational - Summer schools at British Universities, 1959 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Educational - Church and Religion (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Educational - Scholastic Aptitude Test, 1956; Advanced Placement Tests, 1955 - 56 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Educational - Addresses and interviews (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Educational - School and Society, November 29, 1947 (Box 22, Folder 16)